字幕组
ZiMuZu.tv
我叫巴里·艾伦
My name is Barry Allen,
是现今世上速度最快的人
and I am the fastest man alive.
在外人看来  我只是个普通的鉴证专员
To the outside world, I'm an ordinary forensic scientist,
但在尖端科研实验室的朋友们的帮助下
but secretly, with the help of my friends at S.T.A.R. Labs,
我秘密地打击犯罪  寻找跟我一样的超能力者
I fight crime and find other meta-humans like me.
为了阻止邪恶极速者萨维塔
In an attempt to stop the evil speedster Savitar,
我不小心闯入了未来
I was accidentally thrust into the future,
看到他杀死了我心爱的女人
and I saw him murder the woman that I love.
但是我不会再让这事发生了
But I won't let that happen.
我会尽我一切的努力来改变未来
I'm gonna do everything in my power to change the future,
而我是唯一来得及拯救她的人
and I'm the only one fast enough to keep her alive.
我就是  闪电侠
I am The Flash.
《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously on "The Flash"...
古鲁德  抓走了我爸爸
Grodd. He's got my dad.
哈里是我的朋友  我不会就这么放弃他
Harry's my friend. I'm not gonna just abandon him.
我要回地球二
I'm going back to Earth-2.
现在我是猩猩城的领袖了
Now I am the ruler of Gorilla City,
所有的猩猩都会听从我的一切命令
and all the gorillas will follow anything I order.
那是大猩猩古鲁德吗
Grodd the gorilla,
他在通过威尔斯跟我们说话吗
he's talking through Wells?
是啊
Yeah.
这位漂亮的闯入者是谁
Who is this gorgeous intruder?
她叫吉普赛
Her name is Gypsy.
她是回收者
She's a Collector.
打开缺口
Open a breach!
是时候穿越这个疯人院了
Time to warp out of this madhouse.
你将打开缺口
You will open the breaches,
中城就会在古鲁德面前倒下
and Central City will fall before Grodd.
巴里
Barry?
-早上好  -早上好
- Good morning. - Good morning.
现在才六点半  你心情却这么好
You're in a good mood for 6:30 in the morning.
是的  没错
Yes, I am.
我吵醒你了吗
Was I too loud?
我做了早餐
I did make breakfast.
有薄煎饼和华夫饼
We got pancakes and waffles,
还有法式吐司
some French toast,
培根和香肠  全熟的
bacon and sausage, perfectly cooked.
而且我还去买了你很喜欢的深烘焙咖啡
and I picked up some of that dark roast that you love so much.
巴里·艾伦  你怎么了
Barry Allen, what has gotten into you?
跟你一起我就想做这些事
Being with you makes me want to do things like this.
过来
Come here.
我爱你
I love you.
你真的想要这些吗  还是
So do you actually want any of this, or...
是的
Yes.
也要吃点东西
And some of the food too.
好了
Yeah.
太漂亮了
Nice.
你...
What...
在干什么
are you doing?
我在装饰
I'm decorating!
瞧瞧
Look at this place!
你在装饰极速实验室吗
You're decorating the Speed Lab?
是的  我是在装饰极速实验室
Yes, I'm decorating the Speed Lab.
因为  三藩西斯科
You know, 'cause Francisco, you know,
他不让我装饰表层控制室
he wouldn't let me decorate the Cortex,
因为我把那弄得像过圣诞节似的
'cause I made it look oh-so-jolly for Christmastime.
这些球是干嘛的
What are the balls for?
你知道那是什么吗  灯笼
Do you know what those are? Lanterns.
我常说  关了灯就分辨不出
You know what I always say: a fella that can't tell
球和灯笼的人
the difference between balls and lanterns
就是遇到麻烦了
is in trouble when the lights go out.
从前到后
You go front to back.
刷牙的时候  你是从前到后吗
Toothbrushing. You go front to back?
我是转圈刷的
'Cause I'm a small circles kind of guy.
我一直好奇其他威尔斯是怎么刷牙的
I wonder how the other Wells brushes his teeth.
-那个杀人犯  -我们之间的
- The murderer? - I'm fascinated
微妙的差异  让我很着迷
by the subtle differences between us, you know?
-不微妙的差异呢  -比如
- And the not-so-subtle ones. - Like what?
比如我是天才  而你是蠢货
Like the fact that I'm a genius and you're a moron.
好吧
Okay.
派对上见
See you at the party.
闪电侠
第三季
第十四集
真是变了个样啊
Wow. What a transformation.
又变了
Again!
这就是HR对这个团队的贡献吗
So this is H.R.'s contribution to the team?
美国女性财富人物
当玛莎·斯图尔特吗
Being Martha Stewart?
各位  他只是想做点好事
Guys, he's just trying to do something nice.
小心
Heads up!
我真的不太擅长射箭
I'm not really good with this kind of thing.
知道我该做什么吗
You know what I got to do?
我要去星城
I got to take some lessons
找穿着绿精灵衣服的人学几招
from that guy in the green elf suit over there in Star City,
-他叫什么  -绿箭侠
- what's his name? - Green Arrow.
你这是在搞什么
Hey, what is all this?
朋友日
Friend's Day!
-什么  -没错
- What? - Yeah.
-朋友日  -朋友
- Friend's Day. - Friend's?
在我的地球上
Oh, it's my Earth's equivalent
-这等于情人节  -情人节
- of Valentine's Day. - Valentine's Day.
我想  在我们
And I thought, like, after, you know,
打赢大猩猩之后
our success with the gorillas,
我们应该庆祝一下爱
that we should, like, celebrate the love.
有必要吗
Was all this necessary?
当然有  乔  说到爱  你的
Yeah, Joe. Speaking of, where is your--
你的女友呢  因为我想...
your lady friend? 'Cause I would like to--
不  你什么也别想
No, you wouldn't like to do anything.
她在上班  我也该去上班了
She's at work, which is where I should be going.
我...
Yeah, I...
看看我这有什么  女士们先生们
Look what I have, ladies and gentlemen.
我这有你们个人的朋友日卡片
I have your own personal Friend's Day card.
送给你的真爱  韦斯特小姐
For yours truly, Ms. West.
-谢谢你  HR  -队长
- Thank you, H.R. - Captain.
-谢谢你  HR  -一船之长
- Thanks, H.R. - Leader of the ship.
-谢谢你  -太客气了
- Thank-- thank you. - You're so welcome.
你好  杰西·真快客
Oh, hi, Jesse "So Quick".
我也给你那暴躁的老爹做了一张
Yeah, I also made one for your grumpy old dad.
你知道我的喜好吗
Ah, you know what I like?
-你用震波的嘛  -谢谢
- Yo' vibe. - Thank you.
凯特琳
Caitlyn.
我忘记咖啡了
I forgot the coffee!
我让我心跳加速  杰西·快客
"You have sped into my heart, Jesse Quick."
我们俩都是
Oh, well, I guess that makes two of us.
HR和我爸完全不一样
Wow, H.R. is nothing like my dad.
他很亲和  周到  又明白事理
He's so sweeten and thoughtful and understanding.
我们应该告诉他
We should tell him.
告诉你爸说你要搬到这里吗
Tell your dad about you moving here?
-对  -现在吗
- Yeah. - Um, now?
对  HR说永远没有合适的时机
Yeah, I mean, H.R. said there'd never be a perfect time.
必须撕掉创可贴
Just got to rip the Band-Aid off.
-对  -我们走
- Yeah. - Okay, let's do it.
HR的确说得对
H.R. does make a good point.
什么说得对
Yeah, what's that?
打败古鲁德  对团队真的是场大胜利
It was a really big win for the team, beating Grodd.
我们阻止了一场猩猩袭击
I mean, we stopped a gorilla attack from happening.
瞧瞧你  在改变未来
Yeah, look at you, changing the future.
我们都在改变未来
We're all changing the future,
一次改变一个头条
one headline at a time.
我不知道未来会怎么样
Look, I don't know what the future's gonna bring,
但我希望每天都和你在一起
but I hope every day is with you.
所以我想问你
Which is why I wanted to ask you...
巴里·艾伦
Barry Allen,
你愿意做我的朋友吗
will you be my friend?
当然
Always.
这是HR给你做的
H.R. made this for you.
HR就是个白痴
H.R. is an idiot.
有件事我一直想告诉你
So there's something I've been meaning to tell you.
-好  -那我就直说了
- Okay. - So I-I'm just gonna say it.
这样比较明智
I think that's wise.
我要搬来地球一
I'm gonna move to Earth-1.
什么
What?
-我要留下来  -为什么
- I'm gonna stay here. - Why would you do that?
古鲁德已经没有威胁了
Grodd is no longer a threat.
不  不是因为那个
No, it's-- it's not that. Uh...
我想和沃利在一起
I want to be with Wally.
这整件事让我们意识到
This whole thing has made us realize
我们不知道以后会发生什么事
that we have no idea what's gonna happen, you know, and--
如果我们将来遇到什么事
And if we're gonna go through something,
我们想要一起面对
we want to go through it together.
是啊
Yeah.
这家伙
This guy?
你喜欢他吗
You like him?
是的
Yeah.
他让你快乐吗
He makes you happy?
爸爸
Dad...
好吧
Okay.
这就行了
That's it?
你不大喊大叫吗
You're not gonna yell?
你不把东西扔到那边去吗
You're not gonna throw that over there?
你的快乐对我最重要
Your happiness is what matters to me.
你俩都是成年人了
You're both adults.
我尊重你的选择
I respect your decision.
好好相处
Don't screw it up.
好吧  真够诡异的
Okay, that was weird.
我想这意味着咱们得给你找个住处
I guess that this means that we gotta find you a place.
我  要说我们吧
Me? More like us.
有时好像其他所有人
You know, sometimes it seems like everybody else
都收到过爱情甜甜圈
gets to have their love doughnut.
我的爱情甜甜圈在哪
Where's my love doughnut?
爱情很复杂的
Oh, love is complicated.
朱利安在哪
So, uh, where's Julian?
他在伦敦处理一些家务事
He's taking care of some family matters in London.
事先说好了
Just so you know,
我们只是朋友
we are just friends.
对  朋友区间  我很熟悉
Yeah, the friend zone. I know it well.
那档子事我可熟了
Pretty sure I have a permanent residence here.
你知道  也许我该咽下这狗粮
You know, maybe I should just swallow the pill.
或许我的魅力还不够大
Maybe my game just ain't strong.
你的魅力很大
Your game is so strong!
不管怎样
For what it's worth,
我觉得丽萨·史纳特肯定对你有意思
I think Lisa Snart was totally into you.
丽萨·史纳特
Lisa Snart.
不过我可不会让你和她约会的
Not that I would actually let you date her.
西斯科  我保证  总会有个漂亮
Cisco, I promise, there is a beautiful,
聪明的女人  她会促使你
intelligent woman out there who's gonna challenge you
走上人生的巅峰
to be your best version of yourself.
说实话  她可能就在拐角处
In fact, she could be right around the corner.
吉普赛
Gypsy!
这人是谁
Who the hell is this?
我在哪
Where am I?
为什么关着我
Why am I locked up?
我的超能力在这不管用
My powers don't work in here.
是啊  这牢房就是干这个用的
Yeah, it's kind of the point of the cell.
发生了什么
What happened?
我还以为我们是站一边的
I thought we were all on the same page.
我饶了你  你说你会回到地球十九
I spared your life, and you said you'd go back to Earth-19
告诉其他人你杀了HR
and tell everyone you killed H.R.
我就是那么做的
That's exactly what I did.
我告诉议会你死了
I told the council you were dead.
我不信你
I don't believe you.
我不是来带你回去的
I didn't come here to take you back!
我说的是真的
I'm telling you!
那你来这里干什么
Then why are you here?
我不知道
I don't know.
我最后只记得我在地球二上
The last thing I remember, I was on Earth-2...
追捕另一个穿越者
hunting down another breacher.
等等  你刚才在地球二
Wait, you were just on Earth-2?
在哪里
Where?
在非洲丛林
In the African jungle,
我遇见了...
where I saw...
让我猜猜  一只猩猩
Let me guess, a gorilla?
特别高大  脾气很暴躁
Super tall? Anger management issues?
一定是古鲁德控制了她
Grodd must have taken control of her
然后送她来杀死我们
and sent her here to kill us.
但是她在和它不同的地球上
Yeah, but she's on a different Earth than him,
古鲁德的心电感应不能穿越维度的
and Grodd's telepathy can't cross dimensions like that.
古鲁德说它总是很有预见性
Grodd said he always thinks ahead.
就像是逆闪电
Just like the Reverse-Flash.
它没能让你打开缺口
He didn't have you to open a breach,
所以转而利用了吉普赛
so he used Gypsy instead.
所以那说明
So that means...
古鲁德在这里
Grodd's here.
我感觉他不是孤身一人
Something tells me he's not alone.
有他的踪迹了吗
Any sign of him yet?
跟你三十秒前问过那次一样
Not since you asked 30 seconds ago.
他是个巨型大猩猩
Okay, he's a giant gorilla,
还很有可能领着巨型大猩猩军队
who's probably leading an army of giant gorillas.
你怎么会找不到他
How can you not find him?
他可能找到了一种办法
He's probably figured out a way
-扰乱了我们的卫星  -卫星
- to scramble our satellites. - Satellites.
我们现在谈论的可是只聪明的超级猩猩
We're talking about a genius super-ape here.
他还是个诡计大师
And a master strategist
成功地在我的地球上骗过了我们
who successfully fooled us on my Earth.
我们威尔斯可不是轻易被骗的  对吧安全帽
We Wellses, we don't fool easy, do we, hard hat?
别叫我安全帽
Don't call me "Hard hat""
我们得在他伤害其他人之前找到他
We have to find him before he hurts somebody else.
别担心  巴里  我们会找到的
Don't worry, Barry, we will.
每次我以为我们打败他了
Every time I think we've beat him,
他却变得更强大  更聪明
he comes back stronger, smarter,
更危险
and more dangerous.
它在进化
He's evolving.
我一直用同一种办法与他打斗
I keep trying to fight him the same way.
好了大伙  听着  我们只是需要
Okay, guys, look, we just have to come up
想出一个新方法打败他
with a different way to beat him.
我们需要做的是能有一次赶在他之前
What we need to do is get ahead of him for once.
我们可以的  你看到过未来
We can. You've seen the future.
你知道有袭击发生
You know there's an attack.
如果我们搞清楚袭击在哪里发生
If we just figure out where that attack happens,
我们就可以先发制人  打击古鲁德
we can launch a preemptive strike against Grodd.
我们可以在袭击发起前就阻止他
We can stop the attack before it ever starts.
幸运的是  我们有人
And fortunately, we have someone
能够预见未来的事件
who can foresee future events.
在事件发生之前
Before they happen.
好好  只有一个问题
Okay, okay, there's only one problem.
我只能震波到巴里看到的东西
I can only vibe what Barry saw,
一个公交站旁的报道
and a ticker on the side of a bus stop
可给不了我们太多的信息
doesn't give us a whole lot of info.
如果我们拓宽你震波的视野呢
What if we widen the scope of your vibe?
那你就可以看到更多未来的东西
Then you can see more of the future.
是  我可以来做这个
Yes. I can do that.
只需要借你的震波设备一用
Just need to borrow your vibe gear.
-哈里  我就只有这一副  -我会小心的
- Harry, that's my only pair. - I'll be careful.
-我只有这一副  -韦斯特  跟我走
- It's my only pair. - West, come with me.
-你有个工程师的大脑  -是啊
- You have an engineer's mind. - Yeah, sure.
乐意帮忙
Happy to help.
我们需要一切可能获得的帮助
We're gonna need all the help we can get.
你能不能和乔说说  看他能否召集中城警局
Can you talk to Joe, see if he can rally CCPD?
好  我会告诉他
Yeah, yeah, I'll let him know that
一群有思想的大猩猩准备席卷中城了
an army of sentient gorillas is about to storm the city.
他一定会喜欢的
He's gonna love that.
那吉普赛呢  她可是个厉害的超能力者
What about Gypsy? She's a really powerful meta.
是  可我们不知道她是不是古鲁德潜伏间谍
Yeah, but how do we know she's not a Grodd sleeper agent?
她不是  我检查过她了
She's not. I checked her out.
你能说服她帮忙吗
Can you convince her to help?
哥们  她不会拒绝我的
Bro, she won't say no to me.
不可能
No way.
你已经有了三个极速者  一个冰雪女王
You've got three speedsters, an ice queen,
还有一个差不多跟我一样能震波的人
and a guy who vibes almost as well as I do.
你不需要我帮忙来阻止古鲁德
You don't need my help to stop Grodd.
要不要我提醒你
Need I remind you, you're the one
最初是你把古鲁德带到这里来的
who brought Grodd here in the first place.
不是我自愿的
Not by choice!
我当时在地球二追捕我的逃犯
I was chasing a fugitive from my world on Earth-2
结果古鲁德伏击了我
when Grodd ambushed me
把我变成了他的木偶
and turned me into his damn puppet.
好吧  那这就是报复回去的
Okay, so then this is the perfect opportunity
完美机会  对不对
for payback, right?
别告诉我你想要逃跑
Don't tell me you're gonna run away from this.
我从不逃跑
I never run.
那就来和我们一起战斗
Then stand and fight with us.
我们需要你
We need you.
你们需要我
You need me?
你这是想跟我来卢克·弑星者这一套吗
Are you trying to Luke Starkiller me?
如果我是呢
What if I am?
这样就能让你留下了吗
Is that what it's gonna take to get you to stay?
还有个福利
Here's a bonus:
你闲暇时间可以与这张旷世美颜一起度过
you get to spend extra time with this face.
看看这张旷世美颜  来吧
And look at this face. Come on.
有谁会不想和这个帅哥消磨时间
Who doesn't want to get to spend extra time with this guy?
怎么了
What?
古鲁德控制了我的思维时
The things I saw, when Grodd was in control of my mind,
我看见了那个怪物脑中的恐怖场景
the horrors in that monster's head,
那些画面我永远挥之不去
I can never un-see them.
什么恐怖场景
What horrors?
城市被摧毁
The city in ruins.
人民陷入苦难  到处都是死亡
People in pain. Death everywhere.
那就是古鲁德所希望的  计划的
That's what Grodd wants, what he's planning.
很抱歉  西斯科
I'm sorry, Cisco.
这是你的战争  不是我的
This is your fight. Not mine.
如果你不介意的话
Now, if you don't mind,
我还有几个逃犯要抓  所以...
I still have a fugitive to catch, so...
好吧
Okay.
我理解
I understand.
保重  西斯科
Take care of yourself, Cisco.
承认吧  你很喜欢我
Admit it. You are so into me.
韦斯特
West.
那个装置搞得怎么样了
How are we coming along with that gear?
我已经按你的要求全部调整过了
I've made all the adjustments you asked for,
所以现在应该可以用了
so we should be good to go.
很好  谢谢
Good. Thank you.
太好了
Great.
这个究竟怎么能帮西斯科发出不同的震波
Um, how exactly is this gonna help Cisco vibe any differently?
原理很简单
Ah, simple science.
我们加宽了西斯科震波的
We just broaden the overall harmonic resonance
总谐波共振频率
of Cisco's vibrational frequencies
将它们固定在一个时间点上
all while focusing them on a fixed temporal locus.
-再简单不过了  -是
- Couldn't be easier. - Yeah.
不得不说  哈里
You know, I got to admit, Harry,
你对杰西留在地球上这件事表现得这么淡然
I was super surprised at how cool you were
我非常吃惊
with Jesse staying on this Earth.
我以为你肯定会发狂
I thought, for sure, you were gonna freak out
摔东西  或是把某人给丢出去
and throw something or throw someone.
我女儿开不开心是我最关心的事
Well, my daughter's happiness is of the utmost importance to me.
而你可以让她开心
And you make her happy.
我会竭尽全力让她幸福的
I'm gonna do everything in my power to keep it that way.
我很欣慰  韦斯特
I appreciate that, West.
我肯定杰西也会感到欣慰的  在我走后
I'm sure Jesse will too, after I'm... gone.
我们会经常去地球二上探望你的
We're gonna come visit you on Earth-2 a bunch,
这你就放心吧  哈里
so you don't have to worry about that, Harry.
是啊
Yeah, right.
这就是我的全部心愿了
Uh, well, means the world to me,
因为我不知道自己还剩多少时日了
seeing as I don't know how much time I have left.
等下  你病了吗
Wait, y-you're sick?
我身体已经不如从前了
I'm not as well as I once was.
你看医生了吗
Have you seen a doctor?
看了
Yes.
我看过医生了  韦斯特
I have seen a doctor, West.
病情严重吗
Is it serious?
不是吧  哈里
Oh, man, Harry.
天啊
Man. Um...
-很遗憾  -我也是
- I'm sorry. - Me too.
杰西知道吗
Does Jesse know?
我希望你能保密
Appreciate you keep this between...us.
她不知道  我们不想让她为此烦恼
She doesn't know, and we wouldn't want to upset her.
不管你们到了哪特警队都随时待命
SWAT's ready to roll whenever y'all are.
找到古鲁德了吗
We find Grodd yet?
马上就能找到
We're about to.
西斯科  你准备好了吗
Cisco, you ready?
哈里  如果这东西毁了我的脑子...
Harry, this thing, if it fries my brain--
"那是个进步"
"It's an improvement."
-那是"洛奇"吗  -布吉斯·梅迪斯
- Was that "Rocky"? - Yeah, Burgess Meredith.
我准备好了
Yeah, I'm ready.
提醒一下  没有方向的震波
Word of warning. Vibing blind,
就像是在巨浪上冲浪
it's like surfing a monster wave.
你得保证在浪花的上面滑行
You need to stay above the temporal flow,
否则你的意识会被吸下去
otherwise your consciousness can get sucked under.
那样会发生什么
And then what happens?
我不知道
I don't know.
我猜我们会知道的
Guess we'll find out.
等等  什么
Wait, what?
你在哪  拉蒙  你看见了什么
Where are you, Ramon? What do you see?
我在一个十字路口
I'm at an intersection.
橡树山街
州
街
州街和橡树山街
State and Oakhill.
我想这就是袭击开始的地方
I think this is where it goes down.
那里离桥还有一个街区的距离
That's a block away from the bridge.
通往市中心
That leads right to the heart of town.
如果那些猩猩通过了桥...
If those gorillas get over that bridge...
他们瞬间就可以占领城市
They'll overrun the city in no time.
我们阻止了就不会
Not if we stop them first.
大家保持警惕
Eyes wide, everybody.
古鲁德的军队随时都会出现  明白了吗
Grodd's army could be here any second, all right?
还没有他们的踪迹
There's no sign of them.
你确定是这里吗
You sure this is the right place?
根据西斯科所说  是的
According to Cisco, this is it.
时间对吗
Was it the right time?
我们来早了
We're too early.
不  闪电侠
No, Flash.
是太迟了
Too late.
-古鲁德  -我记得
- Grodd. - I remember,
这个人类对你很重要
this human is important to you.
现在...
Now...
他是我的了
he's all mine.
不要
No! Hey!
不要伤害他  你想要的是我  对吗
Do not hurt him. I'm the one you want! Right?
我警告过你  闪电侠
I warned you, Flash.
现在我来地球一
And now I'm here on First Earth
履行我的诺言
to make good on my promise.
等我完事了  这座城
And when I'm finished, this city
还有所有弱小的人类们
and all the puny humans
都会死
will die.
不
No!
乔
Joe!
你还好吗
Are you okay?
我想还好
I think so.
我不明白
I don't get it.
为什么袭击乔·韦斯特警探
How is attacking Detective Joe West
也是古鲁德计划里的一部分
a part of Grodd's plan?
-并不是  -那是为了什么
- It wasn't. - Then what was it?
调虎离山
A distraction.
我才不管福特参议员是不是有疑问
I don't care if Senator Ford is having doubts.
如果部长不同意预算
If the secretary doesn't approve that budget
早上的第一件事
first thing in the morning,
就是大幅削减...
we're gonna have to make some serious cuts--
什么情况
The hell was that?
那只可恶的猩猩这次差点干掉我
That damn gorilla almost got me this time.
不会留下疤的
Shouldn't even have a scar.
你还能记得
Do you remember anything
古鲁德控制你的时候发生了什么吗
from when Grodd was controlling you?
记不清了  只闪过了一些画面
Not really. Just some flashes.
什么的画面
Flashes of what?
那些...  那些画面
They were, like, these images...
是我从没见过的地方
places I've never seen before.
就好像是我看见了他看见的地方
It was like I was seeing what he was seeing.
吉普赛说过同样的事
Gypsy said the same thing.
我知道你那表情是什么意思
Here we go. I know that look.
就是那种"我有办法了"的表情
That's the "I have a genius idea" Look.
几年前在我的那个地球
A couple years back on my Earth,
有个神经学家
there was a neuroscientist
可以修复记忆
that was able to achieve memory recovery
通过对脑损伤者使用颅内磁场模拟器
using transcranial magnetic simulators on brain-damaged--
我们这儿也用  不过用于抑郁症治疗
We use that here but more as a depression treatment.
这个实验中  神经学家
Well, in this experiment, the neuroscientist
将全部能量集中于病人的
focused all the energy on the occipital cortex
枕叶皮质区  使他们恢复
of the patients, allowing them to achieve
几乎全部的记忆
almost full memory recollection.
所以你认为古鲁德
So you think the connection Grodd creates
在被他控制的大脑中所建立的联系
in the brains of those he mind-controls
是双向的
goes both ways?
有可能
Could be.
或许我们能用古鲁德在乔脑中
Maybe we could use Grodd's memories
留下的记忆来推断其计划
that he left behind in Joe to figure out what his plan is.
我们只需制造一些模拟器
We'd just make some TCM simulators.
-只需要一些  -磁铁
- All it takes is some... - Magnets.
将磁铁放在一起  用它们做个头盔
Throw together some magnets, make a helmet out of 'em.
等等  你们要把一堆磁铁
Hold on. Y'all want to put a bunch of magnets
压在我的脑袋上  然后观察
against my skull to look into the mind
一只残忍的变态猩猩的大脑
of a psychotic, murderous ape?
没错
Yeah.
好吧
Fine.
我们就这么做吧
Let's make it happen,
以免古鲁德又要杀其他人
before Grodd tries to kill somebody else.
不会有事的
It's gonna be okay.
没事吧
Is everything okay?
我只是不想再看到我关心的人们
Just tired of seeing the people I care about
处于危险之中
be put in harm's way.
是啊  但我们总会
Yeah, but like always,
一起努力  想出办法的
we're gonna work together and come up with a plan.
我们会阻止古鲁德的  巴里
We're gonna stop Grodd, Barry.
然后呢
And then what?
再把他送回去吗
We just send him back?
他还会再来的
He's just gonna come here again.
我们要彻底结束一切
We have to end this once and for all.
等下
Wait.
什么  你想杀古鲁德
What? You want to kill Grodd?
尖端科研
800层
为什么不行
Why not?
这就是大猩猩城的运转模式
That's how their society in Gorilla City works--
要么杀戮  要么被杀
kill or be killed.
这就是他想要我杀索罗瓦的原因
That's why he wanted me to kill Solovar.
你知道吗  我应该杀了他
And you know what? I should have.
我太过慈悲
I showed too much mercy.
不  你做了对的事  巴里
No, you did what was right, Barry,
一如既往
as you always do.
这才是你成为英雄的原因
That's what makes you a hero.
奥利弗杀了人
Oliver has killed.
他仍被视作英雄
He's still considered a hero.
不错  但他每一天都背负着
Yeah, and he lives with the weight of that decision
那个决定带来的沉重
every single day.
我想有时  阻止坏事发生
I think that sometimes, the only way to stop
唯一的方式
bad things from happening
就是根除起因
is to just get rid of what's causing them.
这到底是因为什么
What is this really about?
古鲁德还是我的死亡
Grodd or what happens to me?
我杀了古鲁德  他的攻击就不会发生
I kill Grodd, his attack never happens,that
那样就会改变未来
changes the future, and...
而你就会活下来
you live, yeah.
你的人性  仁慈
Your humanity, showing mercy,
就是你的与众不同之处
that is what separates you from everyone else.
也是大家都仰仗你的原因
That's the reason that everyone looks up to you.
不要改变你自己  千万不要
Don't compromise who you are... ever.
如果失去闪电侠的特质
Losing what makes The Flash The Flash--
就是救我的代价  我的命不值得
my life isn't worth it if that's the cost to save me.
原来你在这儿
There you are.
你爸爸不会有事的
Hey, you know your dad's gonna be all right.
怎么了
What's wrong?
我在想  我...
Look, I've been thinking, and I...
我想你不该留在这儿
I don't think you should stay here.
我认为  这不是好主意
I think... It was a bad idea.
沃利  你让我留下的
Wally, you asked me.
对  但我不该那么做
Yeah, and I shouldn't have.
我想你应该回到地球二
I think you should go back to Earth-2...
尽可能多陪陪你父亲
spend as much time with your dad as you can.
尽可能多陪陪我父亲
Spend as much time with my dad as I can?
沃利  你在说什么
Wally, what are you talking about?
你爸爸病了  杰西  病得很重
Your dad is sick, Jesse. He's really sick.
他时日不多了
He doesn't have much time left.
他告诉你的吗
Did he tell you that?
很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
他真是不可理喻
He is... unbelievable.
你要做的就是集中注意力
So all you have to do is concentrate
回想古鲁德留下的记忆  好吗
on your memories of Grodd, okay?
好  没问题
Yeah, that won't be a problem.
好了
All right.
死人
Hey, dead man.
真的吗
Seriously?
你和沃利说你要死了
You told Wally you were dying?
-要死了  -你要死了吗
- Dying? - You're dying?
我没说我要...
I didn't say I was, uh...
我只说我不知道自己还有多少日子
I-I said I didn't know how much time I had left.
-我们没人...  -那你到底怎么回事
- None of us-- - Okay, what is wrong with you?
你为了让我留在你身边
Is there seriously nothing you won't say
真的什么都说得出来吗
to get me to stay by your side?
-我不...  -听着  随便吧
- I don't-- - Look, whatever.
我要留在这儿  不管你乐不乐意
I'm moving here, whether you like it or not.
你要做的就是集中注意力
So all you have to do is concentrate
-回想古鲁德留下的记忆  -好
- on your memories of Grodd. - Yeah.
-准备好了吗  -就等你了  死人
- You ready? - Waiting on you, dead man.
一旦我开始被古鲁德操控
Hey, if I start to Grodd out at any point,
马上断电
cut the power off immediately.
没问题
Of course.
好了  乔  你准备好了吗
All right, Joe, you ready?
-好了  -那好
- Yeah. - All right, then.
开...始...了
So here... we... go.
乔
Joe?
我不知道他还会画画
I didn't know he could draw.
就是这样  实际上人人都会画画
Well, that's the thing. Anybody can actually draw.
只是某些人有更发达的视觉皮层
It's just that some have more developed visual cortex
与动手能力
and manual ability, as you know.
现在  这些磁铁激发了他大脑中的那些区域
And right now, these magnets are taking that part of his brain
增强了这些功能
and lightin' it up.
成功了
Well, it worked.
现在我们有了新问题
Now we have a new problem.
我们得查明这是谁
We have to figure out who the hell this is.
晚上好  将军
Good evening, General.
今天的颜色和代码
Color and number of the day.
紫色  246
Purple 246.
你还好吗  长官
Are you all right, sir?
生病了
Sick.
允许进入
好了
Good.
将军
General.
雷诺兹堡 核导弹运输
洛奇
Yo, Rocky.
你还好吗
How you doin'?
我还好  就是...
Yeah, I'm fine. I just...
无论我如何阻止古鲁德
No matter what I do to stop Grodd,
他总能找到新的攻击方式
he just keeps finding new ways to attack,
新的毁灭方式  我...
new ways to destroy, and I...
爱瑞丝觉得我不该杀他
Iris doesn't think I should,
但要结束这一切只能如此
but the only way this ends is if I kill him.
杀他
Kill him.
这或许是我听你说过的
That might be the most idiotic thing
最愚蠢的话
I've ever heard you say.
-等等  什么  -爱瑞丝是对的
- Wait, what? - Iris is right.
如果你不愿听  那就去吧
If you don't want to listen, go ahead,
继续做个傻瓜
keep being an idiot.
我不明白
I don't understand.
不要杀古鲁德
Don't. Kill. Grodd.
哈里  所有人里你应该最明白
Harry, you of all people should understand.
我是说  你为了救杰西也愿意杀人
I mean, you would have killed to save Jesse.
你当时打算杀了极速
You were gonna kill Zoom.
巴里  有无数件事
Barry, there's a thousand things
我做过但并不以为傲
I've done that I'm not proud of.
有一些还是最近做的
Some of them recently.
每次我做那些事
Every time I do one of those things,
下次再做时就越发地容易
it makes it easier to do it the next time.
我看着你与黑暗抗争
I look at you, out there battling the darkness,
带着希望与荣耀  我才想到
with honor and hope, and I'm reminded
总会有别的办法
there's always another way,
总会有的
always.
杀死古鲁德并不是你要的答案
Killing Grodd is not your answer.
拯救生命并不能成为夺取生命的理由
Saving one life doesn't justify taking another.
找别的办法吧
Find the other way.
伙计们
Guys.
需要你们到表层控制室来
We need you in the cortex.
怎么了  西斯科
What's up, Cisco?
遇到一个大问题
We've got a behemoth of a problem.
真是好极了
Terrific.
我们把这位无名氏的画像
So we ran our John Doe image
在每个数据库里都进行了比对
through every database.
过程相当艰难  这家伙简直是个幽灵
And it was tough. I mean, the guy's a ghost.
我们都管他叫杰森·伯恩了
We've been calling him Jason Bourne.
接着HR注意到了一些细节
But then H.R. noticed something.
一开始  真是让我想破了头
Well, at first, it was a real brain-twister,
然后我突然想起了我的地球上
but then I remembered a quote
一位著名诗人阿尔弗雷德·扬科维奇的名言
from a renowned poet from my Earth, Alfred Yankovic--
你说的是怪人阿尔吗
Are you talking about Weird Al?
为什么  因为发型吗
Why? 'Cause of the hair?
快说重点  如果有的话
Get to the point already, if you have one.
当然有  安全帽  看他的头发
I can, hard hat. It's his hair.
标准的军人发型
Standard military cut.
于是我们把画像
So we ran the image through
在国防部数据库中做了比对  然后
the Department of Defense database, and,
用西斯科的说法  "棒呆了"
as Cisco would say, "Yahtzee."
我是会这么说
I would say that.
干得好  HR
Nice work, H.R.
我知道
I know.
国防部数据库里显示他是
DoD has him listed as
空军上将马修·麦克纳利
Air Force General Matthew McNally.
马修·麦克纳利上将  我给你们一次机会
General Matthew McNally, and I'll give you one guess--
猜猜看他负责什么
just guess what he's in charge of.
我知道你要说军事武器
I know you're gonna say military weapons,
但我真的希望你别说军事武器
but I really hope you don't say military weapons.
比那更糟  巴仔
It's worse, Barr.
是核导弹
Nuclear missiles.
麦克纳利拥有最高权限
McNally has the highest clearance.
他可以在十分钟之内让火箭升空
He can have a rocket in the air in less than ten minutes.
卫星现在能正常工作了吗
So are the satellites back to functional?
我们刚做了全面检测
We ran a full diagnostic.
任何被授权发射的核武器
Any nuclear weapon that's authorized to fire,
-都将触发警报  -很好
- an alarm will sound - Okay, good.
是那种声音吗  听起来像是警报
Does it sound like that? That's an alarm.
没错  这就是警报  HR
Yeah, it's that alarm, H.R.
好了
Okay.
短程弹道导弹
Short-range ballistic missile
被授权从雷诺兹堡发射
authorized to fire from Fort Reynolds.
发射前我们还有多少时间
How much time do we have?
几分钟
Minutes.
古鲁德  你干了什么
Grodd, what have you done?
我们能从这里远程阻止发射吗
Can we stop it from here?
军事武器基本用的都是模拟信号
Military weapons are basically analog.
我是说  他们现在还在用软盘
I mean, they still use floppy disks.
我去阻止导弹发射
I'm going after it.
两位  不  听着  感谢你们支持
Guys, no, look, I appreciate it,
但我需要你们待在这里  好吗
but I need you to stay here, okay?
如果我无法阻止导弹发射
If I can't stop it,
需要你们把大家转移到安全地点  好吗
I need you to get everybody to safety, okay?
国防军事区域  非公莫入
好了  我在导弹发射器边上
All right, I'm with the missile.
巴里  把导弹发射车底座上的盖板移走
Barry, to access the keypad, remove the panel
才能操作密码键盘
at the base of the missile vehicle.
好的
All right.
搞定了  下一步怎么办
All right, that's done. What's next?
好消息是  这枚导弹
Well, the good news is, this missile
有个内置的五位取消密码
has a built-in five-digit kill code.
好极了  密码是什么
Great. What is it?
坏消息就是  我们不知道
That's the bad news. We don't know.
说真的吗  那我该怎么做
For real? Ah, well, then what am I supposed to do?
你得尝试每一种数字组合  巴里
You have to try every combination, Barry.
别担心  对于这种发射器
It's okay; with this type of launcher,
你这么做是不会引爆核弹的
you won't set off the nuke.
巴里  模拟器的预测结果显示
Barry, simulators are projecting
发射模拟
楔石城
威胁等级: 极高
中城
成千上万的人会死
that hundreds of thousands will die.
是啊  最好别这样
Yeah, let's hope not.
快点
Come on.
五位数字  有多少种组合
Five digits. How many combos is that?
-我猜大概是...  -整九万种
- I'm guessing it's about... - Precisely 90,000,
如果你不是傻子而是真正的天才
which you would know if you weren't a moron
就会知道
and you were an actual genius.
两枚导弹锁定目标
Two missiles are locked on target.
伙计们  我们需要别的办法  这不管用
Guys, we need something else. This isn't working.
有备选方案吗
Plan B, anyone?
快点
Work!
他还有多少时间
How much time does he have?
15秒
15 seconds.
伙计们  我要别的办法  这不管用
Guys, I need something! This isn't working!
别的办法
Something else!
你只要继续按  巴里
You just got to keep going, Barry.
只需要继续试
You just--just got to keep trying.
六枚导弹锁定目标
Six missiles are locked on target.
起作用了
It worked.
起作用了  我们成功了
It worked! We did it!
发射取消
我们成功了
We did it!
谢天谢地
Oh, thank God.
闪电侠阻止了武器发射
Flash stopped the weapon.
但是他阻止不了我们全部
But he can't stop us all.
进攻
Attack!
发现他们了
Found them.
他们就在城外
They're right outside the city.
朝着政府路和橡山路来了  很快
Heading for State and Oakhill, fast.
那是市中心方向
Which leads right into downtown.
好吧  我们该怎么做
All right, so what do we do?
巴里  我明白
Barry, I know
我们是厉害的极速者
we're speedsters and everything,
但是我们寡不敌众
but we are way outnumbered here.
是啊  他说得对  我们三个怎么能
Yeah, I mean, he's right; how are the three of us
打败那些大猩猩呢
gonna take on all those gorillas?
我们必须打败
We have to.
虽然我恨这些大猩猩
As much as I hate these gorillas,
特别是古鲁德  如果你杀了他
especially Grodd, if you kill him,
其它的也许会撤退
the other ones might stand down,
但是你有可能无法全身而退  巴里
but you might not be able to come back from this, Barry.
你知道的吧
You know that, right?
我知道
I know.
但是还有另一种方法
But there's another way.
不会那样的
It's not gonna come to that.
西斯科  我需要你的帮助
Cisco, I'm gonna need your help.
在地球二追捕她
Tracked her down on Earth-2.
缺口已经打开
Breach is taken care of.
地球十九
谢谢
Thank you.
我们这个地球上
Risky move coming to an Earth
进行跨维度穿越是会被处以死刑的
where interdimensional travel is punishable by death.
尤其我还是那个
Especially when I'm the one
践行法律的人
who's supposed to uphold that law.
我要和你谈谈
I need to talk to you.
我不接受异地恋
I don't do long-distance relationships.
别误会  如果唯一让你犹豫的
Don't get me wrong; this is something
是距离  我非常愿意和你
I'd love to talk about in more detail,
仔细讨论一番
especially if distance is your only hesitation.
但是我来是谈论古鲁德的
But I'm here to talk about Grodd.
好吧  看来你不接受拒绝
Okay, I see you don't take no for an answer.
吉普赛  拜托了
Gypsy, please.
他会毁了我的城市
He's gonna destroy my city.
他会伤害我爱的人
And he's gonna hurt the people I love.
我之前告诉过你  这不是我的问题
I told you before, that's not my problem.
听着  在别人看到你之前快回到地球一
Look, just go back to Earth-1 before someone sees you
否则我就只能公事公办了
and I have to do something that I don't want to.
你告诉我可以用我的超能力做
You know, you told me I could do things with my powers
我从没想过的事情  你是对的
I'd never even imagined, and you're right,
因为我不再震波找人了
'cause I'm not just vibing people anymore.
我在震波他们的感受
I'm vibing what they feel.
你知道此时此刻
And you know what I'm getting from you,
我感知的你吗
right here, right now?
你不只是这样  你像我一样
You're more than this. You're like me.
你想做一些善事
You want to do something good.
得找个东西阻止古鲁德
Look, we need something to stop Grodd,
我需要你帮忙
and I'm gonna need your help getting it.
拜托  做你想做的那个英雄
Please, be the hero I know you want to be.
威尔斯  还剩多久
Wells, how long do we have?
两分钟  巴里
Two minutes, Barry.
哪有两分钟  还剩十秒
Two minutes? Ten seconds!
你连时间都不认得了吗
Can you not even tell time?
我就是说的十秒
That's what I said. Ten seconds.
想到办法要我们三个
So got any pointers on how the three of us
怎么拯救大家并阻止几百头大猩猩吗
are gonna save everyone and stop a few hundred gorillas?
攻击腿部
Go for the legs?
尽量别被抓住
Just try not to get caught,
相信我  他们不会放过我们的
'cause, trust me, they won't let go.
我们可没想过会这样开始
Well, that was not the start we're looking for.
因为
Because...
他们要坚持多久
How long do they have to last?
但愿不要太久
Hopefully not much longer.
你的城市会沦陷  闪电侠
Your city will fall, Flash.
只有一个方法能终结这一切
There's only one way to end this.
你干掉我
You kill me.
但你下不了手
But you won't do that.
在你心中"仁慈"为大
All you care about is mercy.
对  没错
Yeah, you're right.
只不过想阻止你的不只是我
Except I'm not the only one that wants to stop you.
索罗瓦
Solovar!
我要挑战你  古鲁德
I challenge you, Grodd!
而你会再次落败
And you will fall again!
再见  古鲁德
Good-bye, Grodd.
住手  住手
Stop! Stop...
杀戮不是解决办法
Death isn't the way.
他背叛了我
He betrayed me.
我知道  那就让他待在原来的地方
I know, so leave him here, where he's from.
我们不会让他再回到猩猩城
We won't let him go back to Gorilla City ever again.
像我饶过你那样  饶他一命吧
Just spare his life, like I spared yours.
让我们回家
Send us home...
一个不落
all of us.
让一百头猩猩
How long is it gonna take
穿过缺口要花多久
to put 100 gorillas through a breach?
我们整晚都会在这  知道我该干什么吗
We're gonna be here all night. You know what I ought to do?
给我们冲杯卡布奇诺
Whip us up some cappuccino--
所有猩猩都回地球二了
All the gorillas are back on Earth-2.
古鲁德呢
And Grodd?
我联系莱拉了  他被超查组带走了
I called Lyla. He's with A.R.G.U.S.
很好  我不知道你们怎么想
Good. I don't know about y'all,
但我不想再见到
but I don't ever need to see
什么高智商又能心电感应的猩猩
a super-smart, telepathic gorilla again.
我也这么想
I'm with you.
不是说古鲁德
Not that Grodd didn't have
无缘无故就不信任人类
some justification for mistrusting humans.
只是古鲁德善良的一面已不在了
Whatever good was in Grodd is gone.
我觉得他们可以把他
As far as I'm concerned, they can throw him
跟鲨鱼王关进一个笼子
in the same cage as King Shark.
我都会花钱去看它们打斗
I'd pay money to see that fight.
好吧  如果城市不再需要我帮忙
All right, well, if the city doesn't need my help anymore,
那我就回地球十九了
I'm gonna head back to Earth-19.
真的吗
Oh, really?
你做这些都是为了城市吗
So you did all this for the city, huh?
因为我敢肯定你选择帮我们
'Cause I'm pretty sure there's a different reason
有别的原因
you chose to help us.
好吧  只有我知道
That's right. I was the only one
索罗瓦在哪里
who knew where Solovar was.
对  我怎么会忘了
Right, yeah. How could I forget?
别装了
Don't front.
你喜欢我
You're into me.
听着  西斯科  我是说
Look, Cisco, I mean,
哪怕我曾经喜欢过
even if I was...
你也搞不定我
you couldn't handle me.
-再见  各位  再见
- Bye, guys. - Bye.
我会把那姑娘娶回家
I'll marry that woman.
对
Yeah.
好  我最好在丢了饭碗前写下这故事
Okay, I better get this story in before I lose my job.
好
Okay.
你确定不想看看未来
You sure you still don't want to look into the future
看有什么变了吗
and see what's changed?
不用了
No.
我已经不想看了
Think I'm done with that.
-好的  -回家见
- Good. - I'll see you at home.
我和你一起走
Hey, I'll walk out with you.
我和塞西尔有约
I got a date with Cecile.
来吧  我们去找哈里
Come on, guys. Let's go find Harry.
再强调一遍  她是我女儿
To review: this is my daughter.
没什么比她更重要了
There's nothing more important to me.
所以你要好好对我女儿
So you do right by my daughter,
否则无论你在多元宇宙哪里
or there is nowhere in the multiverse
我都能找到你
I won't find you.
爸爸
Dad.
这种事不会发生
They'd have to kill me.
再见了
Bye.
再见
再见  杰西·快客
Bye, Jesse Quick.
总有别的办法  闪电侠
Always another way, Flash.
总有的
Always.
亲爱的
Babe?
那是埃丝特祖母面条吗
Is that Grandma Esther's noodles?
冰箱里有薄荷巧克力味冰淇淋
And there's mint chocolate chip in the freezer.
这是给你的
And these are for you.
这些是为了什么
What is all this?
我最近一直忙着
I've been really busy recently with...
去阻止未来发生
trying to avoid the future.
我却忘了其实还有别的办法
And I forgot that there's always another way.
是什么
What is that?
去创造未来
Making the future...
我们的未来
our future.
我曾祖父在二战结束后
My great-grandfather gave this to my great-grandmother
把它给了我曾祖母
after World War II.
他想在坐船离开前求婚
He wanted to propose before he was shipped out,
但他当时没有钱
but he--he didn't have the money.
三年后  他在伦敦驻扎时
And he bought this three years later
买了这枚戒指
when he was stationed in London.
一路作战穿越法国  最后到柏林
Fought his way across France, all the way to Berlin,and
这枚戒指...
this ring...
一直和他的胸牌挂在一起
around his neck with his dog tags.
当他回来时  她正在布鲁克林海军船坞的
And when he got back, she was waiting for him on the dock
码头上等着他
of the Brooklyn Navy Yards.
他在那里向她求了婚
He proposed on the spot.
我妈妈去世后
After my mom passed away,
乔一直替我保管它
Joe held on to this for me...
直到今晚
until tonight.
-巴里  -爱瑞丝·韦斯特
- Barry... - Iris West,
你愿意嫁给我吗
will you marry me?
愿意
Yeah.
我们心里都明白  你属于维克多
Inside of us, we both know you belong with Victor.
你在他工作中不可缺少  是他前进的动力
You're part of his work, the thing that keeps him going.
好吧  我不明白了
Okay, I'm so confused.
这个是讲美洲战争的吗
Is it supposed to be about the War of the Americas?
你不喜欢吗  这可是我最爱的电影
Do you not like it? 'Cause this is my favorite movie.
没有  我没那么说
No, no, I didn't say that.
可能是我的地球上战争更多吧
I guess we just have more wars on my Earth.
我们也可以看些别的
Well, we can just watch something else.
或者可以什么也不看
Or we don't have to watch anything at all.
你知道我想干什么吗
You know what I could go for?
大贝利汉堡
Big Belly Burger.
我马上就回来
I'll be right back.
谢谢你
Thank you.